flixbus.com 2019-12-31

# Data Privacy → FlixBus

Date: 09/06/2019

We attach great importance to the protection of your personal data. For this reason, data protection at FlixBus Inc has a high priority in collecting, processing and using data.

## 1\.   Collection, processing and use of personal data

### 1.1 Contractual relationship

We process the personal data voluntarily communicated to us (for the contractual processing of ticket orders, for carrying out transport and opening of a customer account or in the context of pre-contractual measures.

To do this, we need your first name, last name and cell phone number. For the required payment processing, the following data may additionally be required: For payment of a booked trip with the credit card, FlixBus Inc requires your full name, email address and credit card data.

### 1.2 Legitimate interests

Due to a legitimate, we process the necessary data for the following purposes:

The data stored for the contract processing and for carrying out the bus trips is forwarded to the performing bus companies and other third parties (e.g., service providers for IT, transport, customer service, sending emails and newsletters, and payment processing) in the course of registration and for processing the ticket sale. In justified cases (e.g., damage to the buses), we reserve the right to forward the customer data to the respective bus transport partners. The data forwarded in this way may only be used by our service providers to fulfill their task and not for other purposes. Insofar as orders are processed, processing takes place in compliance with the requirements for order processing.

In addition to processing ticket orders, FlixBus Inc also uses your data for advertising purposes and for market and opinion research to inform you about offers tailored to your interests via regular mail or newsletters. To this end, we conduct advertising scoring for interest-based advertising based on legitimate interests pursuant. The use of your data for advertising purposes, market and opinion research and advertising scoring can be countermanded at any time by a communication to FlixBus Inc, 2575 Beatrice St, Los Angeles, CA 90066 or to [data.protection@flixbus.com](mailto:data.protection@flixbus.com).

In the context of payment processing, your data may be forwarded to the following payment service providers. The credit card number or other bank details are not stored at FlixBus Inc and forwarded directly to the payment service provider:

Payments are processed by our partner Adyen BV, Simon Carmiggelstraat 6 – 50, 1011 DJ Amsterdam. To prevent and detect fraud, we send your IP address to our partner Adyen BV, Simon Carmiggelstraat 6 – 50, 1011 DJ Amsterdam. Your IP address is stored by Adyen BV in this context. All data is transmitted in encrypted form.

The payment method PayPal is processed by PayPal (Europe) S.à r.l. & Cie, P.C.A., 5th Floor, 22-24 Boulevard Royal, L-2449 Luxembourg. You can find additional information about PayPal data protection in the Data Protection Declaration of PayPal.

## 2.  User login/customer account

You have the possibility to create a personal customer account with us. In the password-protected area of the customer account, you can conveniently manage your bookings and store your data for future trips.

The fields (*) marked as mandatory, which contain personal data, are used only for managing and processing the user account. Only the email address is initially required. We verify your identity with it. As part of the registration, you can voluntarily enter your name, address, or your bank account details.

This data is used both for billing and for the function of automatic pre-filling in future bookings. In addition, you can also voluntarily store your cell phone number for contact in case of delay or change of the trip itinerary.

Provided you have consented to these provisions, the “remain logged in” feature will store persistent cookies on your terminal, which are used to ensure that you do not have to log in again at the following visits to our website. This feature is not available to you if you have deactivated cookies of this type from being saved in your browser’s settings.

You can update or delete you customer account—and consequently your stored personal data—at any time in your personal customer account.

A deletion does not affect the personal data required by legal storage periods for the implementation of the contract.

## 3.  Newsletter

The personal data collected at registration of the newsletter with your consent is used for communication with you (e.g., service messages, system notifications, email confirming your registration, sending user account information, information about your tickets and itineraries, or your travel profiles) as well as for mailing newsletters.

When we get your e-mail address in connection with the sale of goods or services and you have not opted out of this, we reserve the right to send you offers regularly via email for products from our range of products that are similar to those already purchased.

You can countermand the use of your email address and the processing and use of the data for creating user profiles at any time by sending a message to [unsubscribe@flixbus.com](mailto:unsubscribe@flixbus.com) or via the cancel registration link of the newsletter.

## 4.  Data security

We protect the privacy of users on our website and the connected systems using technical and organizational measures. To ensure secure transfer of personal data, we use the encryption protocol SSL 3.0 (RSA-2048 is used as the underlying encryption method for the public key infrastructure.) This procedure is used successfully throughout the World Wide Web. All personal data (name, address, payment data, etc.) are thereby encrypted and consequently securely transmitted on the internet. You can see via a symbol (closed padlock) in the lower window bar of your browser that you are in a secure area.

## 5\. Storage period of data

We store the data as long as it is required for the respective processing purposes (e.g., contract processing, advertising purposes) and for fulfilling trade and tax legal retention provisions.

## 6\. Contact details of the person responsible

The entity responsible for processing personal data is FlixBus Inc, 2575 Beatrice St, Los Angeles, CA 90066, represented by the Managing Directors André Schwämmlein, Arnd Schwierholz, Daniel Krauss, and Jochen Engert.

## 7\. Information and complaint rights

The entity responsible for processing personal data is FlixBus Inc, 2575 Beatrice St, Los Angeles, CA 90066, represented by the Managing Directors André Schwämmlein, Arnd Schwierholz, Daniel Krauss, and Jochen Engert.

## 8.  Information and complaint rights

Pursuant to the basic data protection regulation, you have a right to free information about your stored data and, where applicable, a right to rectification, deletion, limitation of processing and objection to your stored data. In this context, please contact FlixBus Inc, 2575 Beatrice St, Los Angeles, CA 90066or send us an email at [data.protection@flixbus.com](mailto:data.protection@flixbus.com).  

You can contact our data protection officer at [data.protection@flixbus.com](mailto:data.protection@flixbus.com).

In addition, you have a right to complain about data protection to the supervisory agency responsible for us.

## 8\. Use of cookies

When you visit our website, information in the form of a cookie (small text files stored on your browser) is stored. Information about your use of the website is saved there (identification ID, visit date, etc.). With the use of cookies, we facilitate the use of our online offer through various service functions (such as the recognition of previous visits) and consequently can better adapt the internet offer to your needs. You can stop the storing of cookies and delete existing cookies by making the appropriate settings in your browser. The help function of most browsers tells you how to make these settings. If you do not accept cookies, this may affect the service functions of the internet offer. We therefore recommend that the cookie function be left switched on.

In addition, we use third-party cookies for retargeting and remarketing technologies to optimize our web offerings as well as interest-based marketing purposes. The stored surfing behavior is analyzed using an algorithm, so that targeted interest-related product recommendations in the form of advertising banners or advertisements can then be displayed on third-party websites. Without the express consent of the person concerned, the pseudonymized user profiles will not be combined with the personal data of the user of the pseudonym.

Comprehensive information about how to accomplish this on a wide variety of browsers can be found on the following websites: [youronlinechoices](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/de/praferenzmanagement/), [Network Advertising Initiative](http://www.networkadvertising.org/) and/or [Digital Advertising Alliance](http://optout.aboutads.info/?c=2#!/). You can also find information there about how to delete cookies from your computer as well as general information about cookies.

### 8.1 Google AdWords

To optimize our web offerings as well as for product recommendations, we use the technology provided by Google Limited („Google“) (Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland, „Google“) to create pseudonymized user profiles about the surfing behavior of the website visitors for marketing purposes. For this purpose, cookies may be used, which make it possible to recognize an internet browser upon a renewed visit. The stored surfing behavior is analyzed using an algorithm, so that targeted interest-related product recommendations in the form of advertising banners or advertisements can then be displayed on third party websites. Without the express consent of the person concerned, the pseudonymized user profiles will not be combined with the personal data of the user of the pseudonym. The creation of pseudonymized user profiles for interest-based advertising/ad preferences can be refused at any time by [visiting the https://www.google.com/settings/ads page](https://www.google.de/settings/ads). You can find more information about interest-related advertising at <http://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads/>.

### 8.2 Facebook Custom Audiences

This website uses the Retargeting-Pixel Custom Audience of the social network Facebook, 1601 South California Avenue, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA. With the help of the Remarketing Pixel, it is possible to use the visitors of our website as a target group for the advertisements of Facebook ads. For this purpose, a Facebook cookie is stored on your PC. Please refer to the data protection (privacy settings) provisions of Facebook for information about the purpose and scope of data collection as well as the further processing and use of data by Facebook and your options for privacy settings at <https://facebook.com/policy.php> and [https://www.facebook.com/ads/settings.](https://www.facebook.com/ads/settings) You can object to the use of Custom Audiences [ www.youronlinechoices.com/de/praferenzmanagement](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/de/praferenzmanagement/) or for users with a Facebook account [here](https://www.facebook.com/ads/preferences/?entry_product=ad_settings_screen#_=_).

### 8.3. Google Analytics

This website uses Google Analytics, a web analysis service of Google Inc. (“Google”). Google Analytics uses “cookies”, text files, which are stored on your computer and enable analysis of your use of the website. In addition, this website uses the Google AMP Client ID API to link user activities to AMP pages with those on non-AMP pages via Google Analytics. The Google tracking codes of this website use the “_anonymizeIp()” function. As a result, the IP address within Member States of the European Union or in other States of the Agreement on the European Economic Area is only processed further abbreviated to exclude a direct personal reference. The complete IP address is only transmitted to a server from Google in the USA in exceptional cases and abbreviated there. On behalf of the operator of this website, Google uses this information to evaluate your use of this website, create reports about the website activities and provide other services connected with use of the website and internet for the website operator. The IP address transmitted from your browser within the context of Google Analytics will not be associated with other Google data. You can prevent storing of cookies on your computer via a corresponding setting of your browser software. However, we point out that you might not be able to use all functions of this website to their full extent in this case. You can also prevent Google recording data generated by a cookie with respect to your use of the website (incl. IP address) as well as Google processing of this data by downloading and installing the browser plugin available via the following link: <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=de>

### 8.4 adjust

This website/app also uses, among other things, the analysis technology “adjust” of adjust GmbH (“adjust”). adjust runs the analysis using the IP and Mac addresses of users, however, only used in an anonymised form. This makes it impossible to draw conclusions about a natural person. By using this website/app for analysis purposes, you declare your consent to the anonymised data collected being processed in the manner described above and for the purpose cited above. You may object, at any time, to the collection and storage of data by adjust, with effect for the future. Do so by clicking on the following link: <https://www.adjust.com/opt-out/>

### 8.5 Webtrekk

For the statistical evaluation of the websites, we use the technologies of Webtrekk GmbH, Robert-Koch-Platz 4, 10115 Berlin. With the help of Webtrekk’s services, we collect statistical information about the use of our website. Webtrekk GmbH was certified by TÜV in the Web Controlling area. In particular, the collection and processing of tracking data was checked and certified with respect to data protection compliance and data security. Information which your browser transmits is collected and evaluated in the context of the use of this website. This is done by cookie technology and pixels, which are incorporated on each web page. A direct reference to people is excluded at all times. The data collected in this way is used to create anonymous user profiles that form the basis for web statistics. Without the expressed consent of the person concerned, data collected with Webtrekk technology is not used to identify the user of this website personally and is not linked with personal data via the holder of the pseudonym at any time.  
The permission to collect and store data by Webtrekk may be revoked at any time with future effect. For more information on data protection at Webtrekk, please visit the following link[: http://www.webtrekk.com/index/datenschutzerklaerung/opt-out.html](http://www.webtrekk.com/index/datenschutzerklaerung/opt-out.html).

### 8.6 AdClear Campaign Tracking

We use the services of AdClear GmbH, Robert-Koch-Platz 4, 10115 Berlin (“AdClear”) to collect statistical information for campaign tracking and consequently optimize the service offering for our customers accordingly. Cookies are also used for this purpose. The data is collected in a purely anonymous form. Personal data will not be sent to AdClear. AdClear GmbH is certified for data protection in the field of campaign tracking systems by TÜV Saarland.  
If you disagree with the data collection by the AdClear Campaign Tracking, a cookie with the name “adclearoptout” is set for this.  
You have not refused permission for data collection by AdClear.  

### 8.7 Adtriba

On this website, technology from AdTriba GmbH – Beim Schlump 13a, 20144 Hamburg (<https://www.adtriba.com/>) is used to collect and store data, with which usage profiles are created using pseudonyms. These usage profiles are used to analyse visitor behaviour in order to focus on their needs and to improve our offering. Cookies can be used for this. These are small text files that are saved locally on the page visitor’s device and so allow our website to recognize them when they visit again. Without separately issued express consent, the pseudonymized usage profiles will not be merged with the personal data of the user of the pseudonym.

### 8.8 Tapad

Cross-App and Cross-Device Reporting

Company collects and uses cross-app and cross-device information for reporting purposes. Company does not collect PII via its technology, including across apps and devices. Company uses certain techniques to enable its tracking technology to track users across apps and devices, including cookie and ID Syncing and similar practices.

### 8.9 AB Tasty

This website also uses the AB TASTY SAS web analytics service AB Tasty, which is used for A/B and multivariate tests. This service uses cookies to identify a visitor’s browser and analyze the use of this website. The cookies do not collect any personal data. You can find more information about how AB Tasty processes your data at <https://www.abtasty.com/uk/terms-of-use/>. This page also provides guidance on how to disable tracking at any time.

### 8.10 Hotjar

To improve your user experience on our internet pages we use software from Hotjar (http://www.hotjar.com, 3 Lyons Range, 20 Bisazza Street, Sliema SLM 1640, Malta, Europe). Using the software, we can measure and evaluate user behavior (mouse movements, clicks, keystrokes, scroll height, etc.) on our websites. For this purpose, cookies are placed on users’ terminals and data from users such as browser information, operating system, time spent on the page, etc. can be stored. You can find more information about the processing of data by Hotjar at <http://www.hotjar.com/privacy>. You can object to the use of Hotjar’s services at <https://www.hotjar.com/opt-out>.

### 8.11 ADARA

ADARA's cookie collects information about your travel activities and preferences from online travel partner websites, and engage with you through personalized, relevant adverts when you're browsing other websites and social media platforms, and through ADARA analytics services. They may also enable the storing of conversion information used to track, create reporting and optimize the performance of ADARA campaigns. You can learn more about ADARA and opt out at [https://www.adara.com/privacy-promise](https://www.adara.com/privacy-promise.).

### 8.12 Sojern

SOJERN's cookie collects information about your travel activities and preferences from online travel partner websites, and engage with you through personalized, relevant adverts when you're browsing other websites and social media platforms, and through SOJERN analytics services. They may also enable the storing of conversion information used to track, create reporting and optimize the performance of SOJERN campaigns. You can learn more about SOJERN and opt out at <https://www.sojern.com/privacy/product-privacy-policy>.

### 8.13 Awin

This website uses the AWIN technology and services, which is used to understand which website referred a user to this website. Awin measures the success of these referrals and assist the payment of commission to the referring websites. For this purpose, Awin stores cookies on devices of users who are visiting and using our online services in order to record business transactions (placing an order). Awin’s cookies are used to allocate one successful advertisement to a particular business transaction, and to perform corresponding billing services. Personally identifiable information on the user are neither collected nor processed nor used in tracking. Nothing but the information when and on which device (including device’s operating system and browser) a click on an advertisement occurred is stored in tracking cookies. You can learn more about Awin at <https://www.awin.com/us/legal/privacy-policy>. You can also find information about how to delete cookies from your computer at [youronlinechoices](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/de/praferenzmanagement).

### 8.14 Dataxu

We use cookies and similar technologies to collect information about your browser type, operating system, internet provider, IP address, domain name, the pages that you visit on third party websites, the actions that you take on those websites, the date and time of your visits to third party websites, and whether you respond to an online ad.

For mobile users, we collect device types, device make and model, operating system, mobile advertising identifiers (e.g. IDFA on iPhone, Google ADID on Android), operating system device identifier, information about the types of apps you use and the GPS location of your device (subject to your provision of opt-in consent).

We may receive unique identifiers associated with connected TV devices, as well as general information about the video content associated with the delivery of advertising. However, we do not receive information about the specific video content viewed nor associate advertising profiles based on viewed video content without first receiving opt-in consent.

We do not collect personally identifiable information such as your name, address, phone number, or e-mail address. However, please note that our clients may use the platform to deliver advertisements based on previously personal, but now de-identified, pseudonymized or otherwise ‘audience-matched’ information. We do not link, combine or re-identifiy personally identifiable information with information collected through the platform without your opt-in consent.

You may manage your preferences opt out of cookies placed on dataxu websites by clicking here: <https://www.dataxu.com/about-us/privacy/data-collection-platform/>

### 8.15 Snowplow

This website/app uses Snowplow Opensource, an analysis technology of Snowplow Analytics Limited (The Rome Building, 32-38 Scrutton Street, London, EC2A 4RQ, United Kingdom). With the help of analysis technology, we collect statistical data on the use of our website. Information which your browser transmits is collected and evaluated in the context of the use of this website. This is done by cookie technology and pixels, which are incorporated on each web page. The data collected in this way are used to create usage profiles that form the basis for web statistics. You can prevent storing of cookies on your computer via a corresponding setting of your browser software. However, we point out that you might not be able to use all functions of this website to their full extent in this case. You can also prevent FlixMobility from collecting the data generated by the cookie with respect to your use of the website, as well as the processing of this data by FlixMobility, by objecting to such collection and processing using the following link: [data.protection@flixbus.com](mailto:data.protection@flixbus.com)

## 9\. Social Plugins

Our website uses social plugins of the social networks Facebook Inc., 1601 S. California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA, Twitter, Inc., 795 Folsom St., Suite 600 San Francisco, CA 94107, USA, Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway Mountain View, California, 94043, USA, Pinterest, Inc., 635 High Street, Palo Alto, CA, USA, and Instagram Inc., 1601 Willow Road, Menlo Park, CA 94025, USA.

The plugins are located on our product page and are disabled in their initial state. If you click the appropriate button, then you are prompted in a new window to sign in to the social media provider. In this case, a cookie is placed on your computer. If you click on the button or are not logged on to the respective social media provider no cookie will be placed on your computer.

If you are a user of the respective social media provider and are logged in and click the button, this information is sent to your profile at the respective social media provider. If you interact with the plug-ins, for example by pressing the “Like” button on Facebook or by posting a comment, the corresponding information is also transmitted directly from your browser to the social network and stored there. Please refer to the data protection (privacy settings) provisions of the following providers for information about the purpose and scope of data collection as well as the further processing and use of data by the provider as well as your rights and setting options for protecting your privacy:

  * Facebook:[ http://www.facebook.com/policy.php](https://www.facebook.com/policy.php)   
  * Google+: <http://www.google.com/intl/de/+/policy/+1button.html>
  * Twitter: <http://twitter.com/privacy>
  * Pinterest: <http://about.pinterest.com/privacy>
  * Instagram: <http://instagram.com/about/legal/privacy/#>

We and Facebook are jointly responsible for the operation of the Facebook page, and we use anonymous statistical data provided by Facebook on the basis of Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR for the analysis of our Facebook page. The collection and processing of these data is the responsibility of Facebook. Further information about the collection and processing of these data and your rights to Facebook can be found in the privacy policy statement* on our Facebook page.
